<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on lavafroth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on lavafroth</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using an Android Phone as a webcam in NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently had to attend an online meeting for a software development event.
While my PC did have a decent microphone, the built-in camera has been damaged to the extent that the best it can capture is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../pc-camera.jpg" alt="A blurry image taken from my scuffed camera">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a close-up of the moon, it&amp;rsquo;s the refraction caused by the scuffs to the lens plus other sciency stuff I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified enough to explain to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abstracting Structured Patterns in Concurrent Programming</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/abstracting-structured-patterns-in-concurrent-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:58:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/abstracting-structured-patterns-in-concurrent-programming/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I hope this article provides a solid blueprint for building a concurrency management API.
If you have questions or feel that I have missed something, feel free to talk about it in this repository&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/lavafroth/lavafroth.github.io/issues">issue tracker&lt;/a> or the &lt;a href="https://github.com/lavafroth/lavafroth.github.io/discussions">discussion board&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In recent months, I have come across multiple articles talking about the need
of structured concurrency in modern programming languages as a built-in. Notably, in the article &lt;a href="https://vorpus.org/blog/notes-on-structured-concurrency-or-go-statement-considered-harmful/">Notes on structured concurrency, or: Go statement considered harmful&lt;/a>,
the author compares the &lt;code>go&lt;/code> statement used to spawn coroutines to &lt;code>goto&lt;/code> statements used
for jumping to other parts of code in early languages like COBOL.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Switched to NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:29:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I had last posted. I had been spending my time on some programming projects that withheld me from even participating in CTFs.
Tired of this workflow that I somehow spiraled into, I&amp;rsquo;m now seeking to learn new things in an attempt to break out of this workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-end-of-an-overarching-journey">The End of an Overarching Journey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As any of my long time audience might be familiar with, I daily drove &lt;a href="https://archlinux.org">Arch Linux&lt;/a>. A very flexible distribution, Arch allows beginners to get a good grasp of the
Linux way of doing things. It has an amazing package manager as well as &lt;a href="https://aur.archlinux.org">a user repository&lt;/a> for extra software unavailable in the official repositories. It&amp;rsquo;s rather
easy to setup Arch for gaming, thanks to programs like &lt;a href="https://lutris.net/">Lutris&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://usebottles.com/">Bottles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>