<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on lavafroth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on lavafroth</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using an Android Phone as a webcam in NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</guid><description>I recently had to attend an online meeting for a software development event. While my PC did have a decent microphone, the built-in camera has been damaged to the extent that the best it can capture is this:
No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a close-up of the moon, it&amp;rsquo;s the refraction caused by the scuffs to the lens plus other sciency stuff I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified enough to explain to you.
I was aware that one can use ADB to use an Android phone&amp;rsquo;s camera as a makeshift webcam.</description></item><item><title>Abstracting Structured Patterns in Concurrent Programming</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/abstracting-structured-patterns-in-concurrent-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:58:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/abstracting-structured-patterns-in-concurrent-programming/</guid><description>I hope this article provides a solid blueprint for building a concurrency management API. If you have questions or feel that I have missed something, feel free to talk about it in this repository&amp;rsquo;s issue tracker or the discussion board.
In recent months, I have come across multiple articles talking about the need of structured concurrency in modern programming languages as a built-in. Notably, in the article Notes on structured concurrency, or: Go statement considered harmful, the author compares the go statement used to spawn coroutines to goto statements used for jumping to other parts of code in early languages like COBOL.</description></item><item><title>I Switched to NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:29:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</guid><description>Hi. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I had last posted. I had been spending my time on some programming projects that withheld me from even participating in CTFs. Tired of this workflow that I somehow spiraled into, I&amp;rsquo;m now seeking to learn new things in an attempt to break out of this workflow.
The End of an Overarching Journey As any of my long time audience might be familiar with, I daily drove Arch Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>