<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NixOS on lavafroth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/nixos/</link><description>Recent content in NixOS on lavafroth</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:04:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/nixos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Tale of a Frugal Home Server</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/a-tale-of-a-frugal-home-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:04:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/a-tale-of-a-frugal-home-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having run an on-premise server for the past two years, I think my setup has finally
matured enough to be worth talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any point, you can check out the source code for the server&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure &lt;a href="https://github.com/lavafroth/dotfiles/tree/main/hosts/rahu">here&lt;/a> for a concrete example.
For each service I talk about, I will also link the respective definitions in my config.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My minimalist mindset has unsurprisingly aided the architecture of my server.
Throughout the rest of the post, you will come across the following broad strokes:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NixOS Secureboot Shenanigans</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/nixos-secureboot-shenanigans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:26:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/nixos-secureboot-shenanigans/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="key-takeaways">Key takeaways&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This issue only pertains to secureboot on NixOS using lanzaboote. Most Linux users have secureboot disabled. If you are paranoid like me and have enabled it, continue reading.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure to track the latest version of &lt;code>lanzaboote&lt;/code>. (&lt;a href="https://github.com/lavafroth/dotfiles/commit/4d64808ffbc135b5bf5a61df17ef02d7da8452b7">example&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set the PKI bundle location to the newer &lt;code>sbctl&lt;/code> default. (&lt;a href="https://github.com/lavafroth/dotfiles/commit/1fa71734bb3af83b8de9134e68f0153f49a18205">example&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="deprecated-overridescope">Deprecated &lt;code>overrideScope'&lt;/code>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For the past few months, I started noticing this new warning when rebuilding my system with &lt;code>nixos-rebuild&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Painlessly setting up ML tooling on NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/cuda-on-nixos-without-sacrificing-ones-sanity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:18:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/cuda-on-nixos-without-sacrificing-ones-sanity/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: Use the following method only if you wish to have the latest version of CUDA that is
not yet available in the nix-community cache, otherwise follow &lt;a href="https://nix-community.org/cache">this&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>TL;DR:&lt;/em> Save &lt;a href="#the-flake">this flake&lt;/a>, run &lt;code>nix develop&lt;/code> and &lt;a href="#setting-up-pytorch">setup PyTorch as described&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CUDA">CUDA&lt;/a> is a proprietary vendor lock-in for machine learning folks.
Training ML models is incredibly fast with CUDA as compared to CPUs due to the parallel
processing. So if you&amp;rsquo;re doing something serious, you have no other choice besides CUDA as of writing.
Although, OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Triton and ZLUDA are worth keeping an eye on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using an Android Phone as a webcam in NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently had to attend an online meeting for a software development event.
While my PC did have a decent microphone, the built-in camera has been damaged to the extent that the best it can capture is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../pc-camera.avif" alt="A blurry image taken from my scuffed camera">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a close-up of the moon, it&amp;rsquo;s the refraction caused by the scuffs to the lens plus other sciency stuff I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified enough to explain to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Switched to NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:29:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I had last posted. I had been spending my time on some programming projects that withheld me from even participating in CTFs.
Tired of this workflow that I somehow spiraled into, I&amp;rsquo;m now seeking to learn new things in an attempt to break out of this workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-end-of-an-overarching-journey">The End of an Overarching Journey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As any of my long time audience might be familiar with, I daily drove &lt;a href="https://archlinux.org">Arch Linux&lt;/a>. A very flexible distribution, Arch allows beginners to get a good grasp of the
Linux way of doing things. It has an amazing package manager as well as &lt;a href="https://aur.archlinux.org">a user repository&lt;/a> for extra software unavailable in the official repositories. It&amp;rsquo;s rather
easy to setup Arch for gaming, thanks to programs like &lt;a href="https://lutris.net/">Lutris&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://usebottles.com/">Bottles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>