<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on lavafroth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on lavafroth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 07:10:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Java Code Analysis!?! - Web Challenge | PicoCTF 2023</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-java-code-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 07:10:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-java-code-analysis/</guid><description>To get started we are given the username &amp;ldquo;user&amp;rdquo; and password &amp;ldquo;user&amp;rdquo; to log into the BookShelf Pico web application. We are also given the source code of the application.
Taking a look at the src/main/java/io/github/nandandesai/pico/security subdirectory of the project, we see that it uses JWT.
Interestingly, the file SecretGenerator.java in the aforementioned directory contains a weak hardcoded &amp;ldquo;random&amp;rdquo; value 😱.
@Service class SecretGenerator { private Logger logger = LoggerFactory.getLogger(SecretGenerator.class); private static final String SERVER_SECRET_FILENAME = &amp;#34;server_secret.</description></item><item><title>Java Script Kiddie 2 - Web Challenge | PicoCTF 2019</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-java-script-kiddie-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:47:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-java-script-kiddie-2/</guid><description>This is a web challenge involving javascript, meaning most of the solution is going to be client side. We are asked to visit the challenge page.
From here, we can view the source code of the page.
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;jquery-3.3.1.min.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; var bytes = []; $.get(&amp;#34;bytes&amp;#34;, function(resp) { bytes = Array.from(resp.split(&amp;#34; &amp;#34;), x =&amp;gt; Number(x)); }); function assemble_png(u_in){ var LEN = 16; var key = &amp;#34;00000000000000000000000000000000&amp;#34;; var shifter; if(u_in.length == key.</description></item><item><title>Some Assembly Required 3 - Web Challenge | PicoCTF 2021</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-some-assembly-required-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 16:39:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-some-assembly-required-3/</guid><description>This is a web exploitation challenge from 2021. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty old but has less solves as of writing this post. I figured, it&amp;rsquo;s worth talking about.
We are told to visit http://mercury.picoctf.net:60022/index.html where we find a simple textbox prompting us to submit the flag.
Looking at the page source by pressing ctrl u, we see that it is sourcing javascript code from rTEuOmSfG3.js.
&amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;rTEuOmSfG3.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; While examining the javascript, we will notice that it is obfuscated and packed.</description></item><item><title>Kringlecon 2022 Writeup</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/kringlecon-2022-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 10:36:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/kringlecon-2022-writeup/</guid><description>This writeup is rather haphazard as I jumped around from one place to another solving different unrelated challenges. Although the writeup covers all the challenges, it definitely is not sequential. Just wanted to point that out before diving in.
Clone with a Difference This challenge wants us to clone a git repository. It&amp;rsquo;s using git with ssh for cloning which doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work.
git clone git@haugfactory.com:asnowball/aws_scripts.git We can clone this the HTTPS way:</description></item><item><title>A Reasonably Private Firefox Setup</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/a-reasonably-private-firefox-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 12:50:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/a-reasonably-private-firefox-setup/</guid><description>Privacy, something we expect as a default, is dwindling at an unimaginable rate when it comes to browsers. From amidst the sea of mostly chromium based browsers like Google Chrome, Opera and Edge, I&amp;rsquo;d pick Firefox despite the handful of questionable decisions made in the past by the parent company, Mozilla. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I prefer hardening my Firefox setup.
Basic Preferences Let&amp;rsquo;s make the easiest first step, for each of the following preferences, either head to the specified category under the about:preferences page or click the headings themselves.</description></item><item><title>Pixelated - Cryptography challenge | PicoCTF 2021</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-cryptography-pixelated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 09:25:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-cryptography-pixelated/</guid><description>Hey folks! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve made any CTF related posts. Hope this post and the subsequent ones will help me regain some momentum.
Introduction This challenge gives use two images and asks us if we can make a flag out of them. At first glance, both the images look like noise. Upon a quick web lookup of visual cryptography, it appears that these separate images, known as shares of the original image, can be overlayed on each other to reconstruct the original image.</description></item><item><title>The Make Everything Ok Button</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/the-make-everything-ok-button/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 09:20:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/the-make-everything-ok-button/</guid><description>Disclaimer Before I begin, I must warn you that DeepFaceLab is just a tool and it is neither good nor bad. If you use the tool independently or in conjuction with my Docker image, make sure it is for personal education only. Neither the tool nor the image is meant to be used for making illicit or obscene imagery. If you dare to go beyond the words in this disclaimer, you and only you shall be liable for your actions.</description></item><item><title>Google CTF 2022 Treebox</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/google-ctf-2022-treebox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 10:04:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/google-ctf-2022-treebox/</guid><description>This challenge asks for python code as an input, converts it into an AST (abstract syntax tree) and if there aren&amp;rsquo;t any function calls or imports, executes the code. Our goal here is to avoid explicitly calling any functions yet reading the flag located at flag. We also can&amp;rsquo;t import any modules explicitly. If we read the source code provided for the challenge, we can observe that the sys module is already imported.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF I Saw a Little Elf</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-i-saw-a-little-elf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 09:57:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-i-saw-a-little-elf/</guid><description>package main import ( &amp;#34;bytes&amp;#34; &amp;#34;encoding/base64&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/PuerkitoBio/goquery&amp;#34; &amp;#34;io/ioutil&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/http&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os/exec&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; ) const uri = &amp;#34;http://challenges.ringzer0team.com:10015/&amp;#34; // Helper function to wipe a character set // from a given string. func WipeSet(s, set string) string { for _, char := range set { s = strings.Replace(s, string(char), &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, -1) } return s } func main() { // Fetch the challenge page. resp, err := http.Get(uri) if err != nil { log.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF Hash Me Reloaded</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-hash-me-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 09:57:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-hash-me-reloaded/</guid><description>In this RingZer0 challenge, we are to visit the challenge url where we are given 2 seconds to SHA512 hash the message represented by the binary provided string. We must send the response with the request parameter r. Let&amp;rsquo;s write a go program to do that.
First let&amp;rsquo;s declare the url as a constant.
const uri = &amp;#34;http://challenges.ringzer0team.com:10014/&amp;#34; We fetch the challenge page and defer closing its body once the program ends.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF Hash Me Please</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-hash-me-please/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 09:57:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/r0-hash-me-please/</guid><description>In this RingZer0 challenge, we are asked to visit http://challenges.ringzer0team.com:10013/ and are given 2 seconds to hash the provided message using the SHA512 algorithm. We must send the response as http://challenges.ringzer0team.com:10013/?r=response and to do that, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using some Golang.
Let&amp;rsquo;s declare the URI as a constant.
const uri = &amp;#34;http://challenges.ringzer0team.com:10013/&amp;#34; We fetch the challenge page using the Get function from the http standard library, checking for errors along the way.</description></item><item><title>Oh my God, they killed Kenny!</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/oh-my-god-they-killed-kenny/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 09:26:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/oh-my-god-they-killed-kenny/</guid><description>Introduction Despite being infamous for its profanity and dark, satiric humor, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a huge fan of South Park over the years. Now, before you walk away saying, &amp;ldquo;Screw you guys, I&amp;rsquo;m going home&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d like you to try out a random episode of South Park. While you certainly can visit the official website to watch a random episode, today&amp;rsquo;s post will explain a tiny bash script to watch one without launching the browser.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF Bash Jail 3</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:29:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail3/</guid><description>The challenge Logging into the box we are told that the flag is located at /home/level3/flag.txt.
function check_space { if [[ $1 == *[bdksc]* ]] then return 0 fi return 1 } while : do echo &amp;#34;Your input:&amp;#34; read input if check_space &amp;#34;$input&amp;#34; then echo -e &amp;#39;\033[0;31mRestricted characters has been used\033[0m&amp;#39; else output=`$input` &amp;amp;&amp;gt;/dev/null echo &amp;#34;Command executed&amp;#34; fi done We are also told that this prompt is launched using ./prompt.sh 2&amp;gt;/dev/null which means we cannot exfiltrate the flag from stderr since it is blocked.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF Bash Jail 2</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:28:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail2/</guid><description>The challenge Logging into the box we are told that the flag is located at /home/level2/flag.txt
Challenge bash code: function check_space { if [[ $1 == *[bdks&amp;#39;;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;amp;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; &amp;#39;]* ]] then return 0 fi return 1 } while : do echo &amp;#34;Your input:&amp;#34; read input if check_space &amp;#34;$input&amp;#34; then echo -e &amp;#39;\033[0;31mRestricted characters has been used\033[0m&amp;#39; else output=&amp;#34;echo Your command is: $input&amp;#34; eval $output fi done Inference: This time, the check_space function returns a 1 if there are any characters in the input string among b,d,k,s, a semicolon, an ampersand and a whitespace.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0 CTF Bash Jail 1</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:27:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/ringzer0ctf-bash-jail1/</guid><description>The challenge Upon SSHing into the box, we are told that the flag is located at /home/level1/flag.txt
Challenge bash code:
while : do echo &amp;#34;Your input:&amp;#34; read input output=`$input` done Inference and experimenation The script is reading an input, executes it and then stores it in the output variable without ever displaying the output to the console.
I tried a dummy command to see if I could see its stderr since command substitution (backticks) only capture the stdout.</description></item><item><title>Operation Oni, Operation Orchid - Forensics Challenges | PicoCTF 2022</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-forensics-operation-oni-operation-orchid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 07:10:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-forensics-operation-oni-operation-orchid/</guid><description>In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the Operation Oni and Operation Orchid challenges from the PicoCTF competition held in March 2022. Both of these challenges involve the use of tools from The Sleuth Kit suite. In order to follow along, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend installing the suite of tools.
Operation Oni The challenge has an associated instance which we&amp;rsquo;ll need to log into using SSH using the following command:
ssh -i key_file -p 61948 ctf-player@saturn.</description></item><item><title>PicoCTF web challenge: JAuth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-challenge-jauth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 14:49:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-challenge-jauth/</guid><description>The challenge description states that most web application developers use third party components without testing their security. It mentions some past affected companies, then asks us to identify and exploit the vulnerable component for the challenge at http://saturn.picoctf.net:52025/
The goal is to become an admin. We are provied with the username test and the password Test123! to look around.
The challenge is a dummy bank portal. On login, we see the message:</description></item><item><title>Liberating 14GiB of disk space</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/liberating-14gib-of-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:15:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/liberating-14gib-of-space/</guid><description>The idea is simple:
Remove all duplicates, including zero length files Fine tuning: Hand-pick and remove files deemed unnecessary Since the mileage for second step might vary from person to person, I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on the first step.
I chose jdupes as my weapon of choice for finding and removing the duplicates. It&amp;rsquo;s free and open-source and is cross platform.
For a given folder we would run the following to wipe the duplicates:</description></item><item><title>PicoCTF web challenge: Notepad</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-challenge-notepad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:24:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/picoctf-web-challenge-notepad/</guid><description>At first glance the webapp looks like a stripped down version of Pastebin where we can post a text / code snippet. After submitting the query, we are redirected to an html page containing the content of the post.
The first thing I tried was triggering XSS (cross site scripting) with the following:
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;alert(1)&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; The application source directory tree looks like the following:
. ├── app.py ├── Dockerfile ├── flag.txt ├── static └── templates ├── errors │ ├── bad_content.</description></item><item><title>Gadgeting in Python Jails</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/gadgeting-in-python-jails/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 09:52:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/gadgeting-in-python-jails/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. That one CTF that wants to test your object oriented skills by confining you to a python jail. Additionally some might even keep builtins and eval out of reach.
Here is a cool video explanation by @pwnfunction on server side template injection wherein he mentions a way to &amp;ldquo;gadget&amp;rdquo; our way out of Flask&amp;rsquo;s Jinja2 backend to get remote code execution. Kudos to him for sharing this technique.</description></item></channel></rss>