<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workflow on lavafroth</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in Workflow on lavafroth</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:18:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Painlessly setting up ML tooling on NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/cuda-on-nixos-without-sacrificing-ones-sanity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:18:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/cuda-on-nixos-without-sacrificing-ones-sanity/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Use the following method only if you wish to have the latest version of CUDA that is
not yet available in the nix-community cache, otherwise follow &lt;a href="https://nix-community.org/cache"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/em&gt; Save &lt;a href="#the-flake"&gt;this flake&lt;/a&gt;, run &lt;code&gt;nix develop&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;a href="#setting-up-pytorch"&gt;setup PyTorch as described&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CUDA"&gt;CUDA&lt;/a&gt; is a proprietary vendor lock-in for machine learning folks.
Training ML models is incredibly fast with CUDA as compared to CPUs due to the parallel
processing. So if you&amp;rsquo;re doing something serious, you have no other choice besides CUDA as of writing.
Although, OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Triton and ZLUDA are worth keeping an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I Use SWHKD in My Workflow</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/how-i-use-swhkd-in-my-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:17:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/how-i-use-swhkd-in-my-workflow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SWHKD is the project that I have been working on for the past few months as a part of Google Summer of Code for this year.
Now that we are done with the development process, I want to talk about why I wanted to improve the project. Although
the easy answer is to get paid or to get a more production facing OSS development experience,
for me, the most important driving force is using it in my own workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Solemnly Swear to Never Buy a Gaming Laptop Again</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-solemnly-swear-to-never-buy-a-gaming-laptop-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-solemnly-swear-to-never-buy-a-gaming-laptop-again/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Around half a decade ago, I bought an Asus gaming laptop, one I&amp;rsquo;m currently using to write this article.
Although it came preinstalled with Windows, I never let it even boot and instead opted for linux. Bill Gates can cry a river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite switching distros multiple times, one sporadical issue my setup suffered from
was the wireless card dying after a few minutes of booting the box. The only solution to this was to reboot my computer, classic!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using an Android Phone as a webcam in NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:47:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/android-phone-for-webcam-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had to attend an online meeting for a software development event.
While my PC did have a decent microphone, the built-in camera has been damaged to the extent that the best it can capture is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../pc-camera.avif" alt="A blurry image taken from my scuffed camera"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a close-up of the moon, it&amp;rsquo;s the refraction caused by the scuffs to the lens plus other sciency stuff I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified enough to explain to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Switched to NixOS</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:29:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/i-switched-to-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I had last posted. I had been spending my time on some programming projects that withheld me from even participating in CTFs.
Tired of this workflow that I somehow spiraled into, I&amp;rsquo;m now seeking to learn new things in an attempt to break out of this workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-end-of-an-overarching-journey"&gt;The End of an Overarching Journey&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As any of my long time audience might be familiar with, I daily drove &lt;a href="https://archlinux.org"&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;. A very flexible distribution, Arch allows beginners to get a good grasp of the
Linux way of doing things. It has an amazing package manager as well as &lt;a href="https://aur.archlinux.org"&gt;a user repository&lt;/a&gt; for extra software unavailable in the official repositories. It&amp;rsquo;s rather
easy to setup Arch for gaming, thanks to programs like &lt;a href="https://lutris.net/"&gt;Lutris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://usebottles.com/"&gt;Bottles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Liberating 14GiB of disk space</title><link>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/liberating-14gib-of-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:15:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://lavafroth.is-a.dev/post/liberating-14gib-of-space/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove all duplicates, including zero length files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine tuning: Hand-pick and remove files deemed unnecessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the mileage for second step might vary from person to person, I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on the first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose &lt;a href="https://github.com/jbruchon/jdupes"&gt;jdupes&lt;/a&gt; as my weapon of choice for finding and removing the duplicates.
It&amp;rsquo;s free and open-source and is cross platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a given folder we would run the following to wipe the duplicates:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>